<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>MK3Y - Mike &amp; JorDanee Key</title>
        <description>We're 30 somethings working, traveling and investing from the road while raising two kids</description>
        <link>https://mk3y.com/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://mk3y.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 12:37:38 -0700</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 12:37:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>I am an Atheist</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This post has been in the works for some time. Several months ago I came to the conclusion that I am an atheist. It feels appropriate to elaborate on how I arrived here for friends and family who have been curious and concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-history&quot;&gt;My History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My home wasn’t a religious one growing up. I grew up with a single mother. My father wasn’t present in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, my childhood was free of any religious indoctrination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We identified as Christians because it was mainstream and because of family traditions. We celebrated Christmas as the birth of Jesus. Easter as the Resurrection and gave a prayer of thanks on Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t attend regular Sunday services, though. And we weren’t members of any particular church or denomination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in my home, God existed, and Jesus was his son. This is pretty much the view held by most Americans. But not much thought beyond that was ever expressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-path-to-christianity&quot;&gt;My path to Christianity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My life up until my early 20’s resembled a secular one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2004, I was terminated from a job as a contractor for the Navy/USMC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event and a cumulative of other bad choices forced me to re-evaluate the direction of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ego proceeded to implode over the following months as I struggled to make ends meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A former coworker reached out to me at about this time. He gave me a book called, “Maximized Manhood.” This book exposed me to traditional Christian ideas about manhood. At the time, the book resonated with me in explaining why my life was in disarray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He invited me to his church, the first time I had ever gone to a church in my young adult life. And that first Sunday, it felt as though the pastor of this church was speaking to me with his sermon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a talk about manhood and it resonated. In my early 20’s I felt that I didn’t know how to be a man. Or how a man should act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here was that answer, Christianity would teach me how to be a man and fix the brokenness in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God was my father. I was no longer fatherless. And Jesus Christ was my savior, who had paid for my sins on the cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-faith&quot;&gt;My Faith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, I became more involved in my church and felt that God’s calling on my life was men’s ministry. To help lead other broken men such as myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My faith played a daily part in my life and my identity. I had found a community to belong to, a purpose for being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily Bible study and prayer became ritual for me. As time went on, I developed an interest in better understanding my faith. Topics of theology and creationism were of particular interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time, I had a deep personal relationship with Christ. With a rich prayer life, I felt assured of my salvation. I was baptized in my church and received the Holy Spirit and the gifts of the spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-first-questioning&quot;&gt;My First Questioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent six years of my adult life at the church my former co-worker introduced me to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the church collapsed when it came to light that the pastor was having an affair with the youth pastors wife. And that this was not the first time this behavior had occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a blow at first. I questioned what I had placed my faith in, and began to ask, how I knew what I was believing was correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, the Christian response is, man is fallible. We have a sin nature. As so often quoted, all of us fall short the glory of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is at this time I began a regular discussion on the topic of faith with an old friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He exposed me to some of the problems with my church’s teachings of the “prosperity gospel”,  and pointed me towards reformed aspects of theology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened here are a couple rationalizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word of God is still true. But the teachings presented to me were wrong. Because of this, it would lead to sin and other consequences. It could even lead one to believe they are saved, when, in fact, they are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A doubling down on my faith began, and a journey into the young reformed movement started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-second-questioning&quot;&gt;A second questioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011, my wife and I moved to Florida. After searching for a church home, and a few that didn’t fit, we found one in Saint Petersburg. Life Bridge Church seemed like the place for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the pulpit, the pastor preached a reformed approach to Christianity. And I began to read books from authors and pastors like RC Sproul and John Piper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for a time, we were happy and grew in our faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was until the realization that Life Bridge Church is a CULT of personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few families at this time were having issues with the church leadership, and somehow my wife and I got sucked into this. We were subject to humiliation, insults, harassment and flat out spiritual abuse as I became a scapegoat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We promptly left that church. And we moved from Saint Petersburg to Clearwater just to get away from it’s members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event left us both hurting. And we have been outside of the church ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was angry and bitter for about a year after the incident. I spent a great deal of time praying and working it out with God. This lead me to a few questions that kept popping up in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do I believe what I believe?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I know what I believe is correct?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;realizations&quot;&gt;Realizations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so many denominations, and various interruptions of the Bible. Each convinced they’ve got the correct revelation, and their interruption is right. How does one answer this question without blind faith?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked this question of another friend who was visiting in Florida, and his response was shocking. When I presented him with two differing views, he simply stated that the opposing view was in sin and error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FAITH IS A CONVERSATION STOPPER.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith is the thing that causes one to abandon all reason and logic. The more I tried to look at this logically, the more and more it kept leading me to the same conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at the history of the church, world history, other religions, and science. The evidence, when taken in, is overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lead me to the inevitable realization that the God of the Bible most likely does not exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say “most likely”; because I like Richard Dawkins 7 Point Scale laid out in the God Delusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia describes it as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Strong theist. 100 per cent probability of God. In the words of C.G. Jung: &amp;ldquo;I do not believe, I know.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;De facto theist. Very high probability but short of 100 per cent. &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know for certain, but I strongly believe in God and live my life on the assumption that he is there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Leaning towards theism. Higher than 50 per cent but not very high. &amp;ldquo;I am very uncertain, but I am inclined to believe in God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Completely impartial. Exactly 50 per cent. &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rsquo;s existence and non-existence are exactly equiprobable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Leaning towards atheism. Lower than 50 per cent but not very low. &amp;ldquo;I do not know whether God exists but I&amp;rsquo;m inclined to be skeptical.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;De facto atheist. Very low probability, but short of zero. &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know for certain but I think God is very improbable, and I live my life on the assumption that he is not there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Strong atheist. &amp;ldquo;I know there is no God, with the same conviction as Jung knows there is one.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wiki also adds: “Dawkins self-identified as a ‘6’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a short time after my realization, I found myself as ‘5’ on the scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I have since moved towards ‘6’ as I have given it more thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is just no strong evidence to suggest I believe otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atheism is quite liberating. But at the same time, this journey has brought a small sense of sadness and some anger.  It has also humbled me in some ways, and I have some regrets about previously held positions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadness at the energy spent on church and other “Christian” pursuits. Time and energy that instead could of have gone towards my dreams and goals, not to mention lost income given away to churches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regret that I held beliefs like “Homosexuals are deviants and shouldn’t be allowed to be married.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regret that many of the beliefs I held damaged relationships with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anger that I was naive enough to believe in things that seem obvious now. But at the same time, a deep understanding of why and how others believe what they believe. Perhaps sympathy too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anger that those beliefs that I held, do in fact inflict massive societal ill. Cause harm to millions of people in various types of ways. And in some cases are holding our society as a whole back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in this, there is also great relief and peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No longer burdened by the concept of sin, I can make mistakes, dust off my feet and move forward. I am accountable for my mistakes. I am not a broken person who needs Jesus. There is no hole in my heart that only God can fill. These are lies of bondage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new view on life and it’s meaning. It feels richer and more beautiful than before. Rather than living my life for some final reward, I live in the here and the now. The present moment. There is no fear of uncertainty, no fear of hell fire. No fear or worry about whether I have the right theology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to close with a quote by Christopher Hitchens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Death is certain, replacing both the siren-song of Paradise and the dread of Hell. Life on this earth, with all its mystery and beauty and pain, is then to be lived far more intensely: we stumble and get up, we are sad, confident, insecure, feel loneliness and joy and love.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/I-am-an-atheist</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/I-am-an-atheist</guid>
                
                
                    <category>atheism</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>38 Days Remote - 8 Days Left in Florida</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working remote now for 38 week days. The experience has been extremely rewarding. It’s also enabled me to change my families life in a big way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re moving from Florida in 8 days! Yes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been planning and dreaming of doing this since last June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sold all our stuff and moved out of our home. We purchased a Ram truck last July and an Airstream travel trailer last August for this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re heading North to visit our families before heading in the direction of our hearts desires; WEST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be visiting my wife’s family for a reunion in New York during between the end of May and early June. Then we are visiting my family in Ohio during the end of June and first week of July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, our attention is turning towards our biggest dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;living-in-the-american-west&quot;&gt;Living in the American west.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what part of the American West? Well… we haven’t settled on that. That’s why we’ve got the Airstream!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many places we want to visit, see and explore. In a way we want to “try on” different places, spending as little or as much time where we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I suspect we’re going to be in Utah for a couple of months. We visited Utah in 2012 and just fell absolutely in love with the state, and have not stopped dreaming (or talking) about it since. The wife and I love red rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as much as we love red rock, we love snow capped mountains and aspen forests too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colorado, Wyoming, Montana … I could picture our future lives in any one of those states.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/38-days-remote-8-days-left-in-florida</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/38-days-remote-8-days-left-in-florida</guid>
                
                
                    <category>updates</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Big Waves of Change</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In 64 days my family is hitting the road, and moving from Florida. And in 32 days our second daughter will enter the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where are we moving to? Enter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://boldandadventurous.com&quot;&gt;BoldandAdventurous.com&lt;/a&gt; - I’ve always had a passion for the outdoors and adventure. For a few years now we’ve toyed with the idea of selling everything we own and traveling the country. But it always seemed, unrealistic, until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When our first daughter was born, my wife and I began to reevaluate the direction of our lives. One word kept surfacing in my mind, over and over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###MEDICORE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t want to just live for the weekend, ship our kids off to day care and do the suburbia thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my wife’s maternity leave it became clear she did not want to go back to work. I was completely against shipping our child off to some day care. We were in agreement, she’d stay home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife however, still wanted to earn money. Being in tech, I found a job on &lt;a href=&quot;http://weworkremotely.com&quot;&gt;WeWorkRemotely.com&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;http://basecamp.com&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;. Which to my surprise, my wife landed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a trip to Oregon for two weeks we knew that we wanted more than anything to start pursuing our dreams. For us, that meant TRAVEL. But now we where more confident in taking risks to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea was to travel the country while living in an  Airstream. Going and seeing whatever we wanted at whatever pace we chose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that dream is becoming or reality. We purchased a truck, and bought our Airstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, the company I work for agreed to let me transition into a full time remote position. It’s been a huge relief to us in transitioning to this new lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges I was facing was solving the issue of; A. Going back to freelancing B. Find a remote job - All while sticking to our time table and handling all the other things we need to get done. To be honest, I don’t think I could revive my freelance business while doing everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the fact is, I took a risk. I told my company I was planning to move. We knew one of two outcomes was possible. They’d let me go remote or I’d be out of a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you know, safety is an illusion and you’re always one accident away from losing your employment anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the risks, and have a little faith. Things have a way of coming together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the big waves of change coming my way. It’s also part of the reason I’ve begun to neglect my blog again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect that to all change once we are on the road. And that my time will shift for new projects and new adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-MK&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/big-waves-of-change</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/big-waves-of-change</guid>
                
                
                    <category>updates</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Flinch</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Being able to tackle a task without self doubt, or backing down is something I think everyone wants to be able to do. And that’s the core idea behind Julien Smith’s book “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00NLJHGOA/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00NLJHGOA&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=boldadventcom-20&amp;amp;linkId=TB4M63W7P6RBFTTW&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Flinch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=boldadventcom-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00NLJHGOA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-flinch&quot;&gt;What is the Flinch?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julien Smith explains in his book that the Flinch is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In a fight, there is a fundamental difference between boxers and everyone else. The guys who have trained are different. If you hit them, they don’t flinch. It takes practice to get there, but if you want to fight, you have no choice. It’s the only way to win.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“For anything you want to do, finding out how is easy. Do the research and make it happen— or so any book would have you believe. Yet every day, you smoke, gain weight, and stay at your old job. Every day, you do the exact opposite of what you plan to do. Why? “&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The flinch is your real opponent, and information won’t help you fight it. It’s behind every unhappy marriage, every hidden vice, and every unfulfilled life. Behind the flinch is pain avoidance, and dealing with pain demands strength you may not think you have.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julien describes how the flinch is our built in instinct to respond to danger. This “Flinching” instinct while useful to protect us from bears, does no good in our safer world of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julien refers to this as our defective “Defective Alarm System” that remains from the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In your daily life, you might never experience anything dangerous at all. Your life is safe— but you’re flinching anyway. You don’t flinch at bears, because there are none. But you do flinch at the prospect of speaking publicly or joining a gym. You flinch at the doctor’s office. You even flinch for sitcom characters. Anytime there’s potential change, there’s a flinch, whether it’s a threat or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You think the flinch is natural, and part of your life, which it is. But have you ever asked yourself why your stomach tenses up and you can’t watch imaginary characters on a television screen do awkward, embarrassing things? You should.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Think of a bear. You see it, and you react, instantly. You know how to deal because your brain is built to help you survive it: you run, jump, fight, or hide. But that’s not the world you’re in, so instead, flinching happens at job interviews or when you’re asking a girl to the prom.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What these encounters have in common with bears is that they’re changes in the status quo. This used to mean danger, so that’s how your flinch reflex sees them. It attempts to stop the changes from happening, using the same fight-or-flight mechanism it always has.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Your flinch has become your worst enemy. It should be a summoning, a challenge to push forward. Instead, the challenge is getting refused.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the book goes into further detail about how to recognize your flinch and over come it. And the key to doing is recognizing your own flinch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is an excellent read, that one can read in single sitting. I highly recommend picking up a copy of “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00NLJHGOA/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00NLJHGOA&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=boldadventcom-20&amp;amp;linkId=TB4M63W7P6RBFTTW&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Flinch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=boldadventcom-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00NLJHGOA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;” and reading it for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/julien-smith-the-flinch-book-review</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/julien-smith-the-flinch-book-review</guid>
                
                
                    <category>reading</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>10 Day Fast - Into the next 95 Days</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Fasting for me has been something I’ve done for years. In my early twenties I often did it without reason. Later I got into multi-day and intermittent fasting for both spiritual and fitness reasons. I’m a big proponent of n=1 or self experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months I haven’t done any serious fasting, beyond 18 to 24 hour intermittent fasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of my  &lt;a href=&quot;https://mk3y.com/the-next-100-days&quot;&gt;100 Days Personal Challenge&lt;/a&gt; I’ve decided to launch myself into a full on 10 day water fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal here is to enter a state of full ketosis for a few days. To help me get some clarity of thought on a few issues and to strengthen my willpower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quick-explainer&quot;&gt;Quick Explainer:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know what Ketosis is, I’ll explain here. Human bodies are sugar-driven machines: ingested carbohydrates are broken down into glucose, which is used as energy or stored as glycogen in liver and muscle tissue. When deprived of dietary carbohydrates, the liver becomes the sole provider of glucose to feed your hungry organs – especially the brain. As the body enters a fasted state and depletes glucose levels, your liver begins producing ketone bodies from fatty body tissue to use as energy. Thus, you are in a state of ketosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fasting and Ketosis have some unique effects on the brain &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/evolutionary-psychiatry/201104/your-brain-ketones&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, that’s been well documented and studied in science (&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/mind-guest-blog/2013/10/01/the-fat-fueled-brain-unnatural-or-advantageous/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2649682/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2367001/&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;). It’s not pseudo-scientific nonsense like fad cleanses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, from experience I often find myself in a greater state of clarity and thought when in the fasted state. And this might be one of the reason so many religions teach fasting as a way to achieve spiritual enlightenment or to draw closer to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-plan&quot;&gt;The Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next 10 days of this posting, I’ll be in a full water fast. Yes, water only. I will be supplementing that with BCAA’s 10mg in the mornings, walking about 3 miles each day, and using 2tbsp’s of Apple Cider vinegar 3 times a day in 8oz of water. I’ve found from personal experimentation that the Apple Cider reduces hunger cravings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-thoughts&quot;&gt;Other Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tying back into &lt;a href=&quot;https://mk3y.com/the-next-100-days&quot;&gt;100 Days Personal Challenge&lt;/a&gt; I’m going to be reading two books on the subject of Willpower and determination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00NLJHGOA/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00NLJHGOA&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=boldadventcom-20&amp;amp;linkId=YVG4FCQYHCBS7YMR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Flinch - By: Julien Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143122231/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0143122231&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=boldadventcom-20&amp;amp;linkId=ETZ6HJLXH33RRTK3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Willpower: Rediscovering the Greatest Human Strength - By: Roy Baumeister&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I’ll be posting my experiences during this experiment to the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sources&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/evolutionary-psychiatry/201104/your-brain-ketones&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/mind-guest-blog/2013/10/01/the-fat-fueled-brain-unnatural-or-advantageous/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2649682/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2367001/&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/a-10-day-fast</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/a-10-day-fast</guid>
                
                
                    <category>goals</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Next 100 Days, A Personal Challenge</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;100 days from now I’ll be starting a new chapter in my life, fulfilling a lifelong dream. But before that happens, there are a few things I’d like to straighten out about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A matter of fact, these mini-habits are 4 of the 5 pillars of my blog. Read, Lift, Code, Write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###READ
 I’m challenging myself to make time to read a book for 30 minutes a night, every night, for the next 100 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###LIFT 
My fitness has been a sore spot for the past year. I’ve gained nearly 20lbs. So the LIFT goal is 3 parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lifting weights 4 days a week.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Walking 3 miles every day, with a 5 mile walk on Saturdays.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Diet: the most crucial part. I’m a faster, always have been. So I’ll be following a strict intermittent fasting regime combined with strict adherence to a ketogentic diet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###CODE 
It’s what I do for a living. Some days I’m passionate about it, others not so much. But there is always room to expand my skillset. I’m setting aside some free time around lunch daily to learning new skills and working projects that advance my skillset. One thing I’d like to do is find an open source project I can contribute too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I want to wrap up my personal website’s glaringly obvious inconsistencies and ship a working site. Doesn’t need to be perfect, just working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###WRITE
Simple enough it seems. Writing is something of a secret passion for me. I enjoy, but I just don’t do enough of it. Writing is work, and it’s a craft you can learn and get better at. But you can only improve your writing, by writing (and reading).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve set a simple goal of writing daily. And to keep myself on track a goal for this blog, 1 new post a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on tying back into the other 3 pillars, writing about my progress with my fitness. Sharing what I’m learning with code. And writing my thoughts about what I’m reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s it. &lt;strong&gt;GAME ON!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Michael Key commit to the above. Feel free to call me out on twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mike_key&quot;&gt;@mike_key&lt;/a&gt; for updates or if you see me slacking.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/the-next-100-days</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/the-next-100-days</guid>
                
                
                    <category>goals</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Desire Follows Direction</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we get ourselves into a rut, where we just lack the motivation to get things done. We’ve got goals, but no real passion or drive to pursue them. As a consequence of lack of motivation we find it difficult to even start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the key to self motivation is &lt;strong&gt;ACTION&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself, have you ever felt like not doing something, but you did it anyways and then felt better for having done it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s emotion following direction. The plain truth is, that without direction your emotional state will be all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take action in the direction you want to go and your feelings will follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy sage advice; but implementation takes a bit of work, grit and determination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time you don’t feel like getting that task done, just do it anyways, push thru the emotion of not feeling like it. The motivation to complete the task will follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t feel like working out? Work out anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ACT FIRST &amp;gt; FEEL SECOND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/desire-follows-direction</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/desire-follows-direction</guid>
                
                
                    <category>motivation</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Goodbye Blog Comments</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I switch from WordPress to Jekyll.  During that time this site has been without comments. My intent moving forward was to move some of those conversations Disqus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After not much thought, I’ve decided against it completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on just doing some social sharing options at the bottom of each post. Boring, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upside to this is ‘freed up time’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have saved myself a ton of time as I am no longer answering tons of comments every single day, managing spam, and then other assorted pings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone would respond to one of my blog posts with their own post I would get a ping and then I would obsess over what they had said. I would draft epic responses and then sometimes immediately regret that I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been lightly and heavily criticized for not having comments enabled on my blog and how I am less “social” and “engaging” and even “relevant” to the times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whateverz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done with spam, and done with unnecessary blog clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers to freedom and more headroom to spend time on shit that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/goodbye-blog-comments</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/goodbye-blog-comments</guid>
                
                
                    <category>musings</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Why I am Writing</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi. I’m Mike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a husband, father, adventurer and wisdom seeker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a fairly simple objective: I want to become the best possible version of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like you, I’m battling to become better and trying to put my own small dent in the universe all while trying to live life to the fullest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not smart enough to figure out everything myself, so I try to master the best of what other people have already figured out. Sounds simple, doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to do this is to read a lot. And try new things, with a heavy dose of self experimentation. Along the way I write about what I’m learning and doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do this? &lt;em&gt;Charlie Munger&lt;/em&gt; said it best:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The best thing a human being can do is to help another human being know more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/why-I-am-writing</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/why-I-am-writing</guid>
                
                
                    <category>musings</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Be a Content Curator</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Our lives are never static, they’re always changing. So too, your blog is a dynamic representation of your ideas, goals, mission and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in being a content “curator”, giving more care to your blog than just being a dumping ground for your writings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean? Well the definition of “curate” and “curation” is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Curation is generally the selection of, care for and presentation of the objects entered into a collection, whether that collection is physical (such as items in a museum) or digital (such as entries in Wikipedia).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makes sense, right? How does this apply to your blog? Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good Blog Curators Manage, Edit, and Update Old Posts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Block out a specific time every week&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add links to new blog posts on older blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add new and relevant content&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Review/re-write content if necessary (sometimes a set of fresh eyes can help you better write out your ideas)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Leverage the feedback and comments&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Publicize your updates&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that simple. I’ve been applying this to my work here for some time now.  I’ll go back and read things I’ve written and rewrite them. Or update and add new information as it become available. The point is, keeping the content fresh and never letting it go stale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://mk3y.com/be-a-content-curator</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk3y.com/be-a-content-curator</guid>
                
                
                    <category>blogging</category>
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
